Po Tong

powebdev.github.io github.com/powebdev linkedin.com/in/potong

Summary:

Web development specialist with both back-end and front-end skills. Motivated to develop websites with exceptional user support and user experience.

Technical Skills

Language: Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Java

Frameworks/Libraries: Django, Flask, jQuery, Knockout.js(MVVM), Bootstrap, Jasmine, Polymer

Databases: SQLite, PostgreSQL, Google Cloud Datastore

Other: Google App Engine, Linux, Apache, Git, GIMP, Inkscape

Project Experience

Conference Organization App - powebdev.github.io/p4_conference

December 2015

- Developed an API server hosted on Google App Engine.
- Utilized Google's Cloud Datastore for data storage.
- Users can organize and sign up for conferences.

Catalog Website - powebdev.github.io/catalog_project

December 2015

- · Developed a RESTful web app using the Python framework Flask.
- · Utilized SQLite for data storage.
- Implemented third-party OAuth Authentication.
- Users can perform CRUD operations on entries belonging to them.

Website Optimization - powebdev.github.io/webperf

January 2016

- · Optimized critical rendering path of existing website with guidance from PageSpeed Insights.
- Eliminated inefficiencies in website JavaScript to achieve frame rate of 60 fps while scrolling.

Arcade Game Clone - powebdev.github.io/js frogger

January 2016

- Clone of the classic game, Frogger. Game assets and engine provided by Udacity.
- Used JavaScript's pseudo-classical OOP pattern to implement entity classes in game.

Work Experience

Chevron - Lab Technologist

Richmond, CA | July 2014-Dec 2015

- Designed and implemented data acquisition software using Python, C++, and Qt framework.
- Collaborated with principal scientists to devise proposal for new projects.

Lab Support – Lab Technician

Richmond, CA | Nov 2013-July 2014

- · Performed experiments to analyze rock and fluid properties.
- Maintained laboratory equipment including test cells, plumbing system, and computer equipment.

Richmond, CA (510)410-6985 potong616@gmail.com

Po Tong

powebdev.github.io github.com/powebdev linkedin.com/in/potong

UC Berkeley - Lab Assistant

Berkeley, CA | Aug 2012-May 2013

- Maintained physics lecture demonstration website.
- · Organized instructional physics lab.

Berkeley National Lab - Undergrad Research Assistant

Berkeley, CA | Sept 2011-May 2012

- Investigated the properties of superconducting materials with high precision and accuracy on nano scale.
- Created and maintained LabView programs to facilitate experiment.
- Utilized analytical software to interpret and present experiment results.

California Army National Guard - Aircraft Mechanic

Fresno, CA | Aug 2008-Aug 2011

- · Identified and fixed rotary wing aircraft malfunctions.
- · Maintained Material Safety Data Sheets on chemicals used in the workplace.

US Army – Aircraft Mechanic

Ft. Lewis, WA | Aug 2002-Aug 2008

- Performed maintenance on rotary wing aircraft.
- · Created and maintained aircraft parts inventory system using MS Access and SQL.
- · Served as shop supervisor and supervised a team of five.

Certificate

Udacity - Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

December 2015

Education

University of California, Berkeley - Physics and Astrophysics, B.A.

December 2012